Guide to the Nigeria Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Nigeria collection
1830-2013
MS 1553
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
13
(21 boxes)
The collection consists of manuscripts, printed material, and photographs relating to the history of Nigeria and current political, economic, and social conditions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection, MS 605; Pamphlet Collection, MS 1351; African Postcard Collection, MS 1575. Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of manuscripts, printed material, and photographs relating to the history of Nigeria and current political, economic, and social conditions.
Arrangement
The material in the original accession is arranged chronologically, with photographs last. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Education -- Nigeria; Islam -- Nigeria; Local government -- Nigeria; Women -- Nigeria; Borno State (Nigeria); Cross River State (Nigeria); Ekiti State (Nigeria); Kaduna State (Nigeria); Lagos State (Nigeria); Niger State (Nigeria); Nigeria -- Description and travel; Nigeria -- Economic conditions; Nigeria -- Politics and government; Nigeria -- Religion; Nigeria -- Social life and customs; Photographs -- Nigeria; Azikiwe, Nnamdi, 1905-1996; Obasanjo, Olusegun, 1937-; Saro-Wiwa, Ken, 1941-1995; Nigeria. Independent National Electoral Commission
- Inventory
  - Manuscript material from the expedition of Richard and John Lander to Borgu and the River Niger (partial translations, provenance materials included), 1830-1832 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Negroes and West Africa Etc., bound journal of writings and photographs by A. F. Mockler-Ferryman; related materials, 1907-1910 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Mandate of Oba Falolu of Lagos and other children and descendants of the late King Docemo, son of the late King Akitoye, to the delegates of the National Council of Nigeria and the Cameroons on the occasion of their departure to the United Kingdom", 1947 June 26 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Federal government/Federal Republic of Nigeria: official documents, informational booklets, 1949, 1969, 1984-1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "The Chiefdom of Koton Karifi, Kabba Province, Koton Karifi Division," by Thomas Andrew Brown, missionary, [195-?] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General information pamphlets; brochures; booklets, 1956, 1962, 1991-1993, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cultural heritage: printed material, 1956, 1986-1991, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Eastern Nigeria Region: official documents, informational booklets, essays on, 1956-1961, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Kaduna State: official documents, informational booklets, printed materials, [1957?], 1967, 1978-1983, [1988?]-1991, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "The Nigerian Military Forces: a Short Review of Service Conditions in Nigeria"; related materials, 1958, 1982-1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Universities: departmental publications, brochures, booklets, 1959, 1963, 1978-1979, [1986?]-1990, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - The National Convention of Nigerian Citizens (N.C.N.C.): constitution, manifestos, printed materials by and about, 1961-1962, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Newspapers, 1961-1966, 1982-1992 (Box 2, Folder 13 - 15)
  - Employment/labor: statistics and reports, 1963, 1990-1993, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Federal Ministry of Information: newsletters, 1963-1964, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - South-Eastern State: address by executive council to Harold Wilson of Great Britain, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Enugu State: official documents, informational booklets, 1967, 1988-1992, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Enough is Enough: a Challenging Appeal to the Ibos of Nigeria," by Ukpabi Asika, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "Biafra Newsletter", 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - British policy towards Nigeria, British essays on, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Management/technology/commerce: journals, magazines, booklets, newspapers, 1968, 1981-1982, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Lagos State: official documents, informational booklets, 1968, 1984-1993, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Gangan: A Magazine of Western State of Nigeria, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - The Nigerian Journal: publication of the Nigerian Students Union in the Americas (NUSA), 1969 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - "Victory for Unity": texts of broadcast speeches by Phillip Effiong and Yakubu Gowon, Nigerian Armed Forces, [1970?] (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - News magazines, 1971-1993, undated (Box 3, Folder 28 - 29)
  - Youth magazines, 1971, 1981, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Student publications: literary, cultural, political, 1972, [1981?]-1983 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Kwara State: official documents, informational booklets, newspapers/news magazines, 1974, 1982-1993 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Borno State: official documents, informational booklets, [1975?]-1985, undated (Box 4, Folder 33 - 34)
  - Bendel State: white papers, documents, journals, 1977-1980, 1985-1991 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Awolowo, Obafemi: excerpts from writings, memorial newspaper, 1978, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Plateau State: official documents, informational booklets, magazines, 1978, 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - "Students' Islamic Society Branch Organization," by B. Aisha Lemu, Islamic Education Trust, 1979 March (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Nigeria High Commission: newsletters, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - "Planfed News": newsletter of the Planned Parenthood Federation of Nigeria, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Agricultural/rural development: journals, brochures, 1979-1982, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Benue State: official documents, informational booklets, 1979-1984, 1990-1991, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Oyo State: informational booklets, magazines, 1979-1984, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Cartoon books on legal issues, by Alhaji Safi Jimba, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Popular magazines, 1980, 1989, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Nigeria Labour Congress (NLC): booklets, leaflets, 1980-1986, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Workers' Vanguard and other socialist organizations: booklets, journals, newspapers, 1980-1986 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Institute of Current World Affairs: newsletters, 1981 July-September (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Azikiwe, Nnamdi, first president of Nigeria: interview, 1981 September 24 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Kano/Maikesini riots, white papers on, 1981 November (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Napetcor: Magazine of the Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Sokoto State: official documents, informational booklets, magazines, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Women's issues/concerns: magazines, printed materials, 1981-1982, 1991-1992, undated (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Academia/education: journals, related materials, 1981-1984, 1989-1991, undated (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Ondo State: official documents, informational booklets, 1981-1993 (Box 5, Folder 55 - 56)
  - The Ohafia Review (OR): The Magazine of the Ohafia People, 1982 April (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Anambra State: white papers, cultural publications, related materials, 1982-1989 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - National Party of Nigeria (NPN): election materials, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Nigeria Advance Party (NAP): address by Chairman Braithwaite to launch his campaign as presidential candidate of NAP, 1983 February 27 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Al Lim (The Knowledge): Nigeria's Foremost Muslim Quarterly, 1983 June-September (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Nigeria Information Service: newsletters, press releases, reports, 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - "Dikko Affair": excerpts from interviews given by Foreign and Commonwealth Secretary Sir Geoffrey Howe, London Press Service, Central Office of Information, 1984 July 13 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - The Nigerian Journalist: The Official Organ of the Nigerian Union of Journalists (NUJ), 1984 September (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - "The Buhari Administration: One Year After": souvenir publication on the first anniversary of the Federal Military Government of Nigeria, [1984] (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Niger State: official documents, informational booklets, printed materials, 1984-1992, undated (Box 6, Folder 66 - 67)
  - The Profile of Nigerian Leaders: 1960-1993, by Samuel Adelakun Ajay; related biographical profiles, 1984, 1992, undated (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - "Re-elect Shagari & Ekwueme": campaign button, [1985?] (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Meet the Oracle, by Elias Foluso Yosuf: a play dedicated to traditional healing in Africa, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Imo State: official documents, informational booklets, 1987, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Bauchi State: histories of, speeches of leaders, printed materials, 1987-1988, undated (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Balewa, Abubakar Tafawa, first prime minister of the Federal Republic of Nigeria: biographical material, 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Mass Mobilisation for Self-Reliance (MAMSER): booklets, pamphlets, 1987-1990 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Katsina State: informational booklets; photocopies of manuscript material, 1988-1990, undated (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Kano State: official documents, informational booklets, [1988?]-1990 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - "Letter to Nigerian Police," by Niyi Oniororo, National Chairman, Nigeria Council for National Awareness, 1989 October 1 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - "Problems of Local Administration and the Imperative of Transborder Cooperation," by Ahmad Muhammad Daku, Nigeria-Niger Trans-Border Co-operation Workshop, 1989 July 2-8 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Social Democratic Party (S.D.P.): constitution, manifestos, printed materials, 1989-1992, undated (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Political essays, 1989-[1993?], undated (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Never Pity Ladies: short story by Omioye Ajewole, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - Ogun State: informational booklets, [1990?], undated (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - "Political Engineering in Nigeria: Past Experiences, Problems, and Prospects," by Alhaji Aliyu Mohammed, Nigerian Political Science Association, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - National Electoral Commission (NEC): booklets, 1990-1993 (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - The National Population Logo: launching ceremony, Department of Population Activities, Federal Ministry of Health, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Civil Liberties Organization (CLO): reports, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Yobe State: informational booklet, 1992 January (Box 7, Folder 86A)
  - Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation (NNPC): circular letter sent by E. Emmanuel of NNPC to South African businesses, 1992 June 6 (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - Osun State: informational booklet, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - "Islam and Nationhood in Sub-Saharan Africa: the Nigerian Experience": keynote address by Ibrahim A. Gambari, Permanent Mission of Nigeria to the United Nations, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 89)
  - [Foduye, Sheikh Usman B.?]: writings on the Islamic way of life, English translations, Publication and Translation Department, History Bureau, Sokoto, 1992, undated (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - Peoples Solidarity Party (PSP): manifesto, [1992?] (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Women in Nigeria (WIN): booklets, statements, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - "Time for Reconciliation: Inaugural Address to the Nation," by Ernest Shonekan, head of interim national government, 1993 August (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Federal Ministry of Information and Culture: booklets, 1993, undated (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - The American Committee on Africa (ACOA): newsletter, 1994 July 22 (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - "Nigeria: Human Rights Abuses... With Impunity": bulletin of Amnesty International, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - [Kitab al-farq bain wilayat ahl al-islam wa bain wilayat ahl-kufri?]: photocopy of manuscript, undated (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - "How to" books: language-learning and cooking, undated (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - "Facts on Reparations to Africa and Africans in the Diaspora," by The Group of Eminent Persons on Reparations (GEP), Organization of African Unity, undated (Box 8, Folder 99)
  - Root: special edition on Nigeria, British magazine, undated (Box 8, Folder 100)
  - Gongola State: informational booklet on culture, undated (Box 8, Folder 101)
  - "Nigeria Ghana Accord": booklet, undated (Box 8, Folder 102)
  - "Photographs - West Africa," by G. L. Boag, [1907?] (Box 8, Folder 103)
  - "Northern Nigeria": photograph album by T. C. Newton, 1910 (Box 8, Folder 104)
  - Photograph album by J. M. Martill [of the Lagos Defense Force?], 1937 (Box 9, Folder 105)
  - Photographs by Robert S. Boyd, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 106)
  - Photographs by Ifeoma Onyefulu, exhibited at the Africa Centre (U.K.), 1994 (Box 9, Folder 107)
  - Photograph album, unidentified photographer, undated (Box 9, Folder 108)
- Additional Material, Accession 1995-M-202
  - Additional printed materials, 1886-1998, undated (Box 1)
  - Additional printed materials, 1886-1998, undated (Box 2)
  - Additional printed materials, 1886-1998, undated (Box 3)
- Additional Material, Accession 2000-M-044
  - Printed materials
    - 1968-1977 (Box 1)
    - 1998, undated (Box 2)
- Additional Material, Accession 2004-M-038
  - Correspondence of architect J. N. R. Gladstone pertaining to a possible building project for a university in Kaduna, Nigeria, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Clarion" [information bulletin of the National Convention of Nigerian Citizens (NCNC), eastern working committee], 1962 Mar, June (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Our Town Series" [summaries of history, geography, culture, industry] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Agbowa-Ikosi, 1991
  - Ajiran, 1995
  - Apa, [1990]
  - Ebute-Metta, [1990]
    - Igando, [1991]
  - Biography [legend, political] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alakuku [The Gentle Giant Alakuku, by Highbred Maxwell], 1958
  - Awolowo, Chief Obafemi [Martyrdom of, by Adio Mosanya], [1982]
  - Brezhnev, L. I., undated
  - Ezego, Victor, [1998]
  - Art and culture (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Carnival of Regeneration (Association of Nigerian Authors), [2000]
  - Cinema Law as It Affects You (Information Services Department), 1993
  - State Museum Guide (Niger State Council for Arts and Culture), undated
  - Reversing the Trend of the 21st Century (Benin City Art Exhibitions), 2002
  - Elections and constitutions (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Citizens' Forum for Constitutional Reform (C. F. C. R.), [2000?]
  - Constitution of Landlords/Landladies Association, 1993
  - National Elections Commission of Nigeria Manual for Poll Officials, 1998
    - Working Document, Yoruba Constitution, undated
  - Environment, preservation, parks (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Inforterra National Focal Point (Federal Environmental Protection Agency), 1999
  - Old Oyo National Park, [199-]
    - Osun Grove Support Group (OGSG), [1996?]
  - Family and women's enrichment programs (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Centre for Women Development, 1992
    - Workshop on the Family Support Programme, 1995
  - Government achievement, history (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Benue State Executive, [1989]
  - Change of Baton, Ekiti State, 1998
  - Change of Baton, Ondo State, 1994
  - First 100 Days of Mustapha Ismail, 1994
  - A Harvest of Smiles, 2 Years of Democracy in Nasarawa State, 2001
  - Nigeria and the World Current Events, 1993
    - Synopsis of Governor Yar'adua's Achievements, 2002
  - Political reform and support (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Centre for Democratic Studies, [1992]
  - Programme to Support Politicians (The Centre for Conflict Resolution and Peace Advocacy (CCRPA), undated
  - Sani Abacha Foundation for Peace and Unity, [1998]
  - "Southerners: Behold Your Colonisation by the North", [1998]
    - "Unity or Distintegration?" (Nigerian Record, Embassy of Nigeria), 1968
  - Photograph album [approximately 100 photographs, scenes of young white males, African scenery and native life, possibly compiled by a young Englishman], 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Additional Material, Accession 2006-M-015
  - "Abacha's Transition Programme", 1995 December (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Akapta 4, literary journal of the English and Literature Students' Association, University of Benin, Benin City, 1981 May (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alamieyeseigha, D.S.P., speeches
  - "Today, I declare...", 2002 November 16 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "We are here for you", 2003 March 11
  - The Companion, monthly literary magazine, vol. 1, no, 1998 December (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Constitution of National Grassroots Association of Nigeria (NGAN), 1998 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Constitution of the Federation of Akwa Ibom Women Associations (FAIWA), undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cross River State National Park pamphlet, [1980] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Dandali, forum for the creative arts, vol.1, 1986 June (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Democracy Monitor, vol. 4, no. 10, 2002 November (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Fabric Dimensions: The Art of Ada Udechukwu and Elizabeth Ohene," art exhibition program, 1990 September (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "FLOW...The Outpouring," art exhibition program, Pod Communications, 1999 August (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Kano, print of the city of, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Maryam Babangida National Centre for Women Development, Abuja, [1992] (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - News from Nigeria, weekly bulletin, 1964 November- 1965 January (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "News Africa, Special Focus: DSP Alamieyeseigha, The footprints of a champion", 2002 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - North West News, no. 18, 1975 March (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Okikpe, publication of the Diewa Writers' Club, vol. 2, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - The Pivot, magazine published by the Association of Islamic Studies Students of Lagos State University, 1989 December (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Positive Review, a review of society and culture in Black Africa, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Theater Forum, annual magazine of the NigerianUniversities Theater Arts Students Association (NUTASA), no. 1, 1987 March (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - The Trumpeter, publication of the Owo Local Government Area Students' Union (OLGASU), undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Newspapers
      - Body and Soul Series, special publication "Coups!" no.1, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Body and Soul Series, special publication 2 "Igbos in the eyes of other Nigerians" no. 4, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Otona, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Oversize
    - Prints from The Illustrated London News
      - "The blockade of the Mashud Waziris", 1901 December 21 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - "The capture of Yola, Benue, Northern Nigeria, on September 2, by the West African Frontier Force", 1901 November 16
      - "The Opening up of Nigeria: the Expedition against the Aros", 1901 December 21
- Additional Material, 1960-2005; Accession 2010-M-075
  Arrangement
  Materials are arranged as received.
  - Publications, reports, and speeches
    - Adeniyi Adebayo flyer, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Richard Adeniyi Adebayo was the first civilian governor, Ekiti State.
    - "Fayose's 366 Days in Office: profile of achievements" flyer, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Peter Ayodele Fayose was second executive governor of Ekiti State.
    - African Network Magazine, vol. 5, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Rights and Development Bulletin: A Quarterly Publication of Rights and Development Centre-RIDEC, vol. 1, no. 1, 1992 June-September (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - African Heritage Magazine, 1963 October (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "Child Labor Problems and Survival in the New Millennium: The Way Forward," Galilee Foundation, 2003 August 19 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Centrepoint, vol. 4, no. 11, 1982 December (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Air-Transport and Import Manual, by Saka Rajio Audu, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Ìwé S'o-F'áyé-Gbo Nipa Ilé Ise Elétígbá Ròyé, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "The Ibadan North East Local Government," information booklet, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Nigeria Newsletter, 1985 August (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - President Olusegun Obasanjo: The Verdict of the People, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Iwe Itoju Ara Eni: David Sosanya Eweje Egbe Ekiti Parapo Tobalase Egbeji Ajibogusoro, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Transition Programme and the June 12, 1993 Presidential Election (photocopy) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "Nigeria in Transition," report by Zubair Mahmud Kazaure, Ambassador of Nigeria to the United States, 1991 October (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Vona Children's Magazine, vol. 1, nos. 1-2, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Mass Line: A Marxist Cadres Journal, vol. 3, no.1, 1987 May (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Writers Vision: Literary Magazine of the Association of West Africa Young Writers, vol. 1, no. 2, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - AFA Journal of Creative Writing, no. 1, 1982 November (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Legal Aid Council brochure, Olu Oka-Iwu, Umu-Ogbenye, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Our Town Series (Imota, Ikeja, Ayobo, Oshodi, Igando Orudu), 2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Our Culture Series, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Nigerian Women Save Democracy banner (photocopy), Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Alliance Française - Ibadan advertisment for art exhibit of Peters Ogunrinde, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Abuja Environmental Protection Board flyer, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "Lagos Declaration on Land and Resource Rights in Africa", 2002 July 16 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Adopted at the second workshop of the Pan-African Programme on Land and Resource Rights (PAPLRR).
    - Networker: Newsletter of the Nigerian Popular Theatre Alliance (NPTA), vol. 1, 1989 June (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - The Parakeet: a magazine of the Bayero Literary Society, a special convocation edition, 1990 February (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Progressive Action Congress (PAC) manifesto, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "The Next Few Days," a press statement issued by the Committee of Ten after the cessation of the Biafra War, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Make Poverty History in Nigeria flyer, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Tips on HIV/AIDS, produced by Community Peoples Action Against Aids (COPEAIDS), 2004 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Chronology And The Study of IGALA History To C.1830 A.D., by Joseph N. Ukwedeh, Department of History, Ahmadu Bello University, Zaria, 1984 February 18 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "The Declining Militancy of Nigerian Women Since Independence," paper by Gloria Chuku, 1994 June (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Presented at the 38th Congress of the Historical Society of Nigeria at the Ahmadu Bello University, Zaria.
    - Asiwaju Bola Ahmed Tinubu: A Great Patriot, by Adeoye A. Arogun, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Brief biographies of Kebbi State Executive Council members, Circa 1998 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - PRONACO flyers (2), 2005, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
      PRONACO is a coalition of over 150 Nigerian organizations and nationalities working to organize a People's National Conference.
    - How To Speak To Girls And Win Their Love, by J. Abiakam, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "The Inaugural Speech of President Olusegun Obasanjo", 1999 May 29 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - All Peoples Party manifesto, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Azikiwe, Nnamdi
      - "Respect for Human Dignity," inauguaral address as Governor-General and Commander-in-Chief of the Federation of Nigeria, 1960 November 16 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - "Bravely Struggling Against Odds," speech as first president of the Federal Republic of Nigeria, 1963 October 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Institute of Current World Affairs bulletins (BSQ 36-41), by Bowden Quinn, 1981 July-October (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Independent National Electoral Commission (INEC)
      - "Manual for Election Observer", 1998 November (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - "Manual for the Registration of Voters", 1998 October (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - "Training Manual for Poll Officials for the Local Government Council Election", 1998 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - "Guidelines for Registration of Voters", 2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)